我们要用电视机了!
We need the TV,Mike.
我正在看电视剧呢!
Can't you see I'm in the middle of a show here.
我有比这更好看的。
Yeah,well,I got a better show.
妈妈把我们以前拍的录像有选择地又录了一遍。
Mom took all the old movies and put them on tapes so that we can see them.
为什么？
Why?
那会很在意思的。
Well,this ought to be fun.
快点，Ben。
Hurry up,Ben.
来前排。
Front row.
爸爸，你是想让我献丑吗？
Dad,you are embarrassing me.
不是挺有意思的吗？
What? You're not excited about seeing yourself in diapers ...
看看你自己包着尿布流着口水的样子
with drool running down your chin?
呵呵，他的样子只要照一下镜子就能看到。
He can just look in the mirror to see that.
噢，Mike小时候是个漂亮活泼的孩子。
Oh,Mike was such a cute little baby.
行了，我现在要去温课了。
Alright. Look,I have to go to study,OK?
我从没听你说过温课。
What's the matter,there's a full moon?
呃，真对不起我不能和你们一起分享家庭的欢乐。
Yeah,I am really very sorry I'm going to miss out on all this family fun.
不过，当然，也希望能和你们一起来看，
Gee I do really love it too.
我们在一起像好朋友，可是我……
You know when we pal around like this.But hey,I have to stu....
Mike，你妈妈花了很大精力来翻录。
your mother has gone to a lot of trouble putting these films on tape.
算了，既然他不愿意看……
It's OK. If he doesn't want to see them.
他想看。
He does.
爸爸，你是说我不用去温课了？
Dad,you are suggesting that I shouldn't study?
是的，是这样的。你温课的时间实在是太多了
Yes,I am. Mike,I think you are spending far too much time studying
而傻乎乎地盯着电视看的时间太少。
and too little time staring blankly at the TV.
Ben，我可不想再等你了。就先放你的带子了。
Ben,we are not waiting for you,your tape is first.
我来了我来了我来了。
Let's go,let's go,let's go!
Ben，你晚饭吃得并不少。
Ben,you just ate a full dinner.
又不是为我，是给我亲爱的家人们准备的。
This is not for me,this is for my family who I love.
好，我放了。
Here we go!
你刚才说先放我？这可是Mike。
Hey. You said the first tape was me,this is Mike.
噢！Mike看上去就像一小段香肠。
Gee,Mike,you sure look like a lady.
我不想看了。
Guy alright,I'm staying.
你们不该这样让我献丑。至少等Ben睡着以后。
All right,and the least you could do is put off my humiliation until he's asleep.
那样我就太扫兴了。你觉得怎么样maggie？
Well,this sure cuts into my fun.,and how about you,Maggie?
对，让Mike献丑就是我翻录像带的主要原因之一，
Yes,humiliating Mike was one reason I had these movies transferred.
可要是他停止说这些酸溜溜的话，
But if he'll stop make snide comments
却谈点陪衬的音乐助大家的兴
and join in the fun by playing a little background music,
那么五年的钢琴课就算没有白上。
just so 5 years of piano lessons don't go down the drain.
好吧好吧好吧，你们这种兴致可真要我的命。
All right,look,I know this family fun is going to kill me.
这个，是我的录像带。
This is my tape.
（Mike音乐声）他在发狂，我知道。
She's a maniac,maniac I know.
他要跳舞如同以前从没跳过一样。
As she's dancing like she's never danced before.
他在房里我就不放了。
I'm not playing this while he's here.
请你们大家都深沉一点，安静地看带子好吗？
Can you guys be a little bit mature and just let a tape play?
这是什么？这是谁？
What is this? Who is this?
呵呵，这些镜头你们肯定早就忘了。
I bet you even forgot you had these.
爸爸，你可从没说过你还有个小丑的弟弟。
hey,dad you never told us you had a brother who was a geek.
那是爸爸，小丑就是他。哈哈哈。
That's dad,he's the geek.
-= Subripped by Susie Shi =-       2007.07.15
噢，爸爸你别拿出来。
Oh,come on,
你要知道妈妈把这些录像翻录下来花了很大的精力。
after all mom went to a lot of trouble putting all these movies on tape.
对。不，没关系，要是他不想看那也没什么。
Ok,if he doesn't want to see them,that's OK.
噢，maggie，我当然非常想看，当然。
Oh,Maggie,I want to see my tape,yes.
听我说，咱们来看我的。
Hi,I know,let's watch my tape.
不不还是继续放我的带子吧。我会感到很自豪的。
Oh,no,no. I will be proud to show my tape.
Yeah
谢谢你Mike。
Thank you,Mike.
这就是你在大学里领导的那个高级乐队？
This is the far out group you led in college?
那当然了，野性热情的乐队。
That's us---the Wild Hots.
别笑了，这个名字倒也很贴切，既有野性又有热情。
Come on guys,that were the perfect name. They were wild and they were hot.
都是些小孩。哈哈哈。
and they were all babies.
你们上电视了。
You were on TV?
对，摇滚乐天才选拨赛，我们代表州参加全国决赛。
Yes,the rock and roll talents which we were the state finalist from Road Island.
我还记得你穿那套衣服来找我时我爸爸的反应。
I still remember my dad's reaction when you came to pick me up in that costume.
他说你的模样像个越共。
He said you look like a vietcong.
他又不像我们那么年轻风流。
Yeah,I was younger than him like we were.
他那里也就是你这个岁数。
He was the same age you are now.
不是。
No.
是的。
Yes.
不是。
Really?
是的。
Really.
不是，他应该在朝气一点。不……
No. He was pushing forty odd...
快看，他在扭屁股，真恶心。
Ah,they're doing the twist.
呵呵…我看玉米花也不多了，我再去给你们拿点。
Well,I think we're low on popcorn and I'll get a little more.
哈哈哈，亲爱的，真是对不起。
Oh,honey,I'm sorry.
哈哈哈…我肚子都笑疼了。
Alright,I'm out of here
还是看看我的带子吧。
Hey,I know. Let's watch my tape.
Ben，晚会已经结束了。
Ben,the party is over.
噢……
Ah.
今天晚上你的话不多。
You are very quiet tonight.
你不声不响好像你根本不在这。
In fact,you are so quiet it's like you are not even here.
Jason？亲爱的，我在跟你说话呢。
Jason,honey I was talking to you.
对不起。
Sorry.
我在想你看到年轻的你，感到现在老了。
I think seeing yourself that young has made you feel a little old.
老了？哈！
Old? Ha!
事实上我甚至猜想你在浴室里盯着镜子看着自己
In fact I would guess you were in that bathroom staring in the mirror probably
也许是在寻找白的胸毛。
looking for gray hairs.
你这话可就错了。
well,you couldn't be more wrong.
你真的以为我是那种在寻找白毛的人吗？呵呵。
I'm hardly the kind of guy who goes looking for gray hairs.
请你原谅，算我说错，
I'm sorry,you are right.
你当然没在寻找白毛了。
That's ridiculous. Of course you weren't looking for gray hairs.
我是年轻人。
I'm a young man.
真对不起，你对你自己的年龄从来没有这么敏感过。
Ok,I'm sorry. It's just that you've never been so sensitive about your age before.
可我并不敏感，
I'm not now,either.
即使像你指出我们初会时我已经到了你父母的年龄，
Even know as you pointed out,I am the same age as your parents were when we met,
这话也不准确当时你父亲比我还大六个月。
which is not even true because your dad was six months older.
再见妈妈。
Bye,mom.
Ben，你要去哪？
Ben,where are you going?
斯丁其家，我和爸爸说过了。
Stinkey's,I told dad.
Ben!
Ben？
妈妈。
Mom.
我很高兴你和爸爸说过要去斯丁其家。
I'm glad you told your father that you were going to Stinkey's. but your father
可你爸爸不知道我要你整理自己的房间。
doesn't know that I wanted you to clean your room this morning.
妈妈。我已经答应让他看这盘有爸爸滑稽样子的带子。
But mom I promised Stinkey he could see the tape of dad looking funny.
不行。这可绝对不行。
No,absolutely not.
那样我就看不到斯丁其的妈妈发胖以前的照片了。
Then I don't get to see the pictures of Stinkey's mom before she got fat.
Ben，回房间去，不收拾干净不准出来。
Ben,go to your room and don't come out until it's clean.
妈妈再见，我要回学校去办点事。
See you later mom. I'm going to go over to the school yard and shoot some hoops. Ok?
好的。办点事？Mike你等一下。
OK. Hoops? Mike,wait.
我的房间已经收拾干净了。
No,my room's already cleaned mom.
不
No.
我的干净衣服都已经挂好了，脏衣服都放篮子了。
No my clean clothes are in the drawer and my dirty clothes are in hand.
Mike！我要说的都不是这些。
No,Mike,that's not what I want to talk about.
你想说我是白干？
You mean I did all that for nothing?
Mike，我要请你帮个忙。
Mike,I want to ask you a favor.
什么忙？
What?
昨天晚上我们看了录像以后
you see after watching all those old movies last night,
你爸爸感到自己老了
well your father started feeling old.
他是老了。
Well he is.
我说的老是指完了。走下坡路的意思。
No,I mean old as in out of it,over the hill.
Yeah.
Mike，我想请你帮我使爸爸能够感到年轻一点，
Michel please,I want you to help me make your father feel a little younger.
难道你就这么不理解？
Is that so hard for you to understand?
他娶了个像你这么年轻漂亮的人，怎么会觉得老呢？
Hey,mom. How can he feel old when he's married to a young fox like you?
Oh,Michel,would you please play a little basketball with your dad? And..
Mike,我请你去跟爸爸打一场篮球吧。还有，
做做游戏？
Throw the game?
这个？
Well.
去跳水，
Take a dive.
好，
Yeah.
但别告诉他。
And no one will know about it.
很对。
Right.
好，那好吧。抓弄爸爸我是行家。噢爸爸。
OK. No problem. I'm an old hand at fooling dad. Oh,dad!
呵呵，这么好的一个儿子，这么年轻漂亮的母亲。
Such a nice boy. Such a foxy young mother.
真是个好球。
Hay,nice drive dad.
没说的，我是行家。
what can I say. I'm good.
再来。
Here we go!
好，开始。爸爸，今天我都没法招架了。
Here you are,you are so quick today here.
顺便问一句，是有意让我赢？
Yes. You wouldn't by any chance be letting me win,would you?
让你赢？开玩笑，我有意让你赢？！
Letting you win? Are you kidding,Why would I want to do that?
我不知道，也许因为你妈妈不愿意承认她错了。
For one thing your mom doesn't like to admit when she's wrong.
妈妈？
Mom?
她干嘛要认为你觉得老了？我说……
And why would she think that you feel old. I mean…
我提醒你Mike，
I'm warning you Mike.
别对你爸爸装出一副恩人的样子好吗？
Don't start patronizing your old man,I mean father.
和你较量我还是能行的。知道吗？
Because I can still keep up with you.
我知道，爸爸。
Yeah right dad.
把你的看家本领全拿出来。
Oh,really. Come on,take your best shot,
比赛结束时看谁会伸舌头。
let's see who sucker and winner at the end of this one. OK?
好啊。
All right?
来吧，真正的比赛别弄虚作假。
Sure. None of that hot dog stuff.
来吧。来吧，
Real game,real game.
除非你怕出洋相，是不是那样？
Unless you are afraid to be humiliated?
那样你就去参加女子队！
I'll understand. are you going to try out for the girls team this year?
来吧。
No
很好，有对手了。
OK,lucky shot.
好了，我都进了二十八个了，不打了。
Come on dad,it's twenty-eight. Am I banked
好，我这次就放你一马。
OK,all right,I let you off the hook this time.
不行，爸爸，
Come on,dad.
你就差二十五分了，怎么可以停下不干了呢？
Only twenty-five more points and you're right back in it.
Ben，你没有看见他打累了吗？
Come on,Ben. Can't you see the man is tired.
噢，你是怕我会赶上去吧？
Oh,what's the matter? Afraid I'm going to catch up?
我只是休息一会。
I was just getting my second wind.
再接再厉，爸爸，你会赢的，你一定要把他打败。
All right,dad. Come on,you can do it,shut him down.
好。
Ah..(falling down.)
来吧。怎么了，爸爸，你没事吧？
Come on dad. Hey dad,are you all right?
只不过滑了一下。
I slipped on something.
怎么回事？
What is it?
脚扭了。
I turned my ankle.
我早知道打得太久了，做父母的就是不听话。
Look,I knew you couldn't play too long. You know parents never listen.
你用不着来唬我，让我歇一会就会好的。
No,I'm fine. All right. Just give me a minute,I can walk it off.
我说爸爸，我累得一秒钟都坚持不了，别玩了。
Hey look dad,I am really bushed. I couldn't play another second. I…
好吧。
OK.
我现在要去学校参加一场比赛。好了再见。
OK.I am going to go over to the school yard and get a game,right? See you later.
爸爸，我认为你是一个摇滚歌手。
Dad,I think you are a rock player.
我知道怎么去做！
Yeah,I know how to play.
尤其是你这样的年龄。
Especially for a guy of your age.
Ah!
别担心爸爸，我来照顾你。
Don't worry,dad. I'll take care of you.
Ben，你在这干嘛？
Ben,what are you doing here?
这是我的家！
I live here.
这会你该带爸爸出去才是！
You're supposed to have dad out of the house by now?
你要我怎么办？总不能不让爸爸上厕所！
What do you want from me? The man has to go to the bathroom.
Ben，爸爸呢？
Ben,where's your dad?
大概在厕所里。
In the bathroom I hope.
这照片怎么样，Ben？
So what do you think,Ben?
我认为这玩意会使他心情更不好。
I think this is going to make him even more depressed
不，你爸爸一看到这张照片马上就会恢复这种情形
Oh,no. Ben. Once he starts to play rock and roll,he's going to start to feel like this again.
真会那么灵？
That's good?
你不信吗？
You bet!
开聚会之前，这玩意放哪？
Where do you want to stash this thing until the party?
放厨房。我试图让你爸爸从大门出去。
OK,in the kitchen. I'll have your father go out the front door.
我来开门。
I'll get it.
我是戴夫·萨克斯，专门代客人去办聚会。
I'm David Sax from party animal party rentals.
来得太早了。
You are early.
赶早不赶迟。
That's our policy.
不！
No.
我没说错。
Yes,it is.
不，我是想说，让爸爸惊喜一下，可他现在没离家。
No. It's supposed to be a surprise for my dad and my dad is still here.
无赖？
Bummer.
走吧，Ben。
Let's go,Ben.
啊，我明白了。
No,maybe I can…
Ben，去动物园可是你的主意，咱们走吧。
Come on,Ben. This is your idea to go to the zoo,let's go!
今天一定很带劲，我要在蛇馆里呆他个一整天。
This is going to be great. I want to spend the whole day at the snake house.
你们谁都不想去？
Anybody else want to come?
因为我有事不去。
No,I've got things to do.
Carol?
噢，我是多么喜欢看笼子里的那些飞禽走兽，可是
Oh,no. Darn it! You know how I love to see Gods creatures in cages,but ..
我得温课。
I have to study.
快走。
Let's roll!
不！你们从厨房出去。
No,you have to go to the kitchen.
不！
No!
厨房的地板是湿的。
Carol,the kitchen floor is wet.
那你们从边门出去。
Well so is the porch.
Carol.
Carol？
妈妈你看……
Mom.
看来出路都断绝了。Ben，我们只好呆在家里。
Well,apparently there's no way out,Ben,I guess we'll have to stay here.
不。
No!
究竟是怎么回事？
What's going on here?
噢，我知道了。
Oh,I know.
现在地上可能已经干了，你们就从厨房出去吧Jason！
The kitchen floor is probably dry by now. If you go out that way,Jason.
谢谢你maggie！
Thanks Maggie!
好了，你们就从厨房出去吧。
So,the kitchen,it is then.
今天你们可解放了。
Are you four all right?
Mike，那是什么？
Mike,what's this?
你说什么？
What's what,dad?
你弄得乱七八糟的。
What's the mess you are making?
呃，你所讲的乱乱七八糟其实就是我的美术课作业，
This mess as you call it,just happens to be my project for art class.
题目是你要放洋葱我就杀了你。
I can't hold the onions or I'll kill you.
我们走。我们走！
Let's go,let's go,let's go!
Seavor，你真行，哈哈。这孩子还会画画。
Seavor,you're good! And the kid can paint.
试试看，喂喂喂，声音再大点，
Hello,testing one two three. Louder Carol.
女士们先生们，罗斯斯宾斯基……
Ladies and gentlemen...Bruce Springsteen!
Mike!
Mike？
怎么了妈妈？
Mom?
小点声，要干的事还很多。
Can you hold it down we still have a lot to do.
说得对妈妈。
OK,mom. No problem.
现在不到一小时了，都准备好了？
Oh,we have less than an hour left. Is everything ready?
Wola!
女士们先生们，麦克唐纳……
Ladies and gentlemen! Madonna!
Carol，你也闹上了。
Carol,not you too!
我说妈妈，如果这也不能使爸爸开心你就和他离婚。
Mom. If this doesn't cheer dad up I think you'll have to divorce him.
这一招会灵的。
Of course it'll work.
见到他的老朋友老乐队他的人生观会彻底更新
He'll be seeing his old friends,his old band,it will give him a whole new outlook.
（门铃响。。。）
(The door bell rang.)
我去开门。Carol你跟Mike再多吹点气球。
I'll get it. Oh,Carol,would you and Mike put up some more balloons?
好的。
OK.
看上去你真是精神极了，好像一点也没变。
You look sensational. You haven't changed a bit.
维克，
Rick!
Oh,Maggie!
你好吗？
How are you!
野性的热情！
Wild and hot!
呵，只是变了一点。呵呵。哗，
Oh,maybe just a little bit. Oh,wow!
我还从来没在这么高级的场合演出过呢。
The Wild Hots never played in a place this classic before.
孩子们，这是维克。维克，这是Carol和Mike。
Kids,this is Rick. Rick,this is Carol and Mike.
嗨。
Hi!
Maggie，哈哈。有件事Maggie，
Oh. Maggie. By the way,Maggie.
今晚的演出有点美中不足
The Wild Hots is going to sound a little thin tonight.
键盘手不来了。
We don't have a keyboard man.
沃伦他会来的。
Warren said he'd be here.
可他被冠心病折腾了一下。
Well,he's had a little coronary.
天啊。
Oh dear!
情况不严重，睡上个把星期就好了。
Nothing serious. He's going to be up in about a week or so.
没关系，Mike你来顶替键盘手好吗？
Wait a minute. Mike can fill in on keyboards.
不行，我一点也没有研究过，那种老派.破烂….
Hay,Mom. I don't know those stupid,fol....
经典的音乐
classics.
不，要是你识五线谱就比我们高明得多了。
If you know five chords then you know two more than we do.
挺浪漫。
Radical?
妈妈，这样闹下去很可能爸爸会去跳河自杀。
Mom,I think we go through with this,there's a good chance that dad is going to drown himself.
有这么严重吗？
No,I don't think it sounded that bad
Maggie，有阿斯匹林吗？
Maggie,do you have any aspirin?
我保留我的意见。
I rest my case!
好吧,好吧你说得对。可你让我怎么办，
Ok,Mike. You're right,but what am I supposed to do?
难道让我把客人们都撵走吗？
I can't just throw all these people out.
好，你听着，咱们会有办法的
I don't know mom,but we can handle this.
我到厨房里放把火。
I can set the kitchen on fire.
不行，我舍不得厨房。
No,I like the kitchen.
好了算了,算了，那爸爸的办公室。
Oh,I know. How about dad's office?
听我说，还是让我来处理吧。
No,it's OK. I'll handle this.
维克？维克？
Rick? Rick? Hay!
请大家注意
Excuse me,everyone.
现在咱们的计划有一点小小的改变。
We've had a slight change of plans
我听说Jason被医院叫去看急诊了
and I've just learned that Jason has been called to the hospital on an emergency
在另一个州。
in another state.
我理解,我理解，我跟你们一样感到扫兴。
I know,I'm as disappointed as you are,
可是Jason两天之内不会回来。
but he won't be back for days
来了！奇怪来了这么多人。
Surprise! What's with you people?
今天是怎么回事？多少年没见了？你们好啊。
What's this? How are you? Oh it's been years.
Maggie今天是什么日子啊？
Maggie,what's the occasion?
女士们先生们，野性热情的创始人魔王Jason Seaver！
Ladies and gentlemen,. The founder of Wild Hots Jammins Jason Seavor
你好吗？见到你很高兴。
Hay,how are you,nice to see you!
这下可好了，你们认为会怎么样？我看会非常顺利。
I think it's going well,do you think it's going well? I think it's going well.
真是太好了，沃伦在哪？
This is great,oh,where's Warren?
他？他心脏病发了。呵呵。
Oh,he had a… he had a heart attack.
什么？
What?
很快就会好。
OK,he'll be fine.
他才三十八岁。
He's thirty-eight years old.
对，他终于懂得了不能和小伙子相比。
I guess he's finally learned that he can't keep up with the youngsters.
对不起Jason，能和你谈一分钟吗？
Excuse me,Jason,can I talk with you for a minute?
最好简短一点。
Better make it quick.
你相信吗？38岁心脏病就要发作。
Can you imagine that? A heart attack at thirty eight!
亲爱的，我的计划是不知道这个情况的。
Oh,honey,I had no idea when I planned this.
那么，历克的脑壳呢？
What about Rick's crone dome?
脱发早的人也是常见的。
Well,a lot of men lose their hair early.
对，尤其是在核电站工作的人。
Yeah,if they had nuclear waste in their shorts!
我组织这个聚会绝不是想让你难过。
The last thing I wanted to do with this party is depress you.
我并没有难过。
I'm not depressed
那是不开心。
No. you are too.
不，我没有。
No,I'm not.
瞧，这帮人的模样连我的情绪都坏了。
Seeing how these guys look now even depresses me.
他们的脸上确实有几条道道了。
Oh,they do have a few miles on them,don't they?
几条道道？全国所有的公路网都在上面了。
A few miles? How about the entire inner state high way system?
他们的年龄和我差不多。
And they are the same age as I am.
亲爱的，和他们相比你象是长生不老仙了。
Oh,honey,compared with them you look like Rickey Shrouder.
对，没错，是这样。
Yeah,yes,I do.
我比不老仙还要年轻。
Younger than Rickey Shrouder.
可我和他们是相同的岁数。我都成奇迹了。
And I'm the same age as these guys,not that that matters.
Jason，从这两个星期以来我一直都想告诉你……
Jason,I've been trying for two weeks to tell you that you weren't old.
我会不会听？不会。
But would I listen? No.
老兄，我们已经排了一遍了，立刻要上演了，
Hey Dude. We knocked the rust off the edges and we are really cooking
魔王该上场了！
but we need the jammer.
野性热情乐队从没让观众失望过！
This songs for you. It's going to make you wild and hot.
One,two,three,four.
1，2，3，4……
Let's take those old records off the shelf.
Sit and listen to them by myself.
Today's music ain't got the same soul
as that old time rock and roll,
Call me a rebel call me what you will.
Say I'm old fashioned say I'm over the hill.
Today's music ain't got the same soul
as that old time rock and roll.
I love that old time rock and roll.
That kind of music does soothe my soul.
I reminisce about the days of old,
and that old time rock and roll.
爸爸，我跟不上你的节奏了。
dad,I can't keep up with you.
你可千万别走神！
don't you forget it,kid.
I love old time rock and roll,
that kind of music to smooth a sole,
I reminisce about the days of old,
and that old time rock and roll.
If I give my heart to you,
I must be sure from the very start,
that you would love me more.
Jason，你要弹到什么时候？
Jason,how long are you going to play guitar?
我向你保证，就弹几分钟。
Just a few minutes,I promise.
If I trust in you,oh please.
maggie，黑乎乎的我没法弹了。
Hey Maggie,I can't play in the dark.
可是我能……
Well,I can.